

### **Madeline Johnston**

## **Portfolio** maddyjohnston.github.io

**Email** maddy.johnston@sky.com

**Mobile** 07443337509















#### **Profile**

I'm a final year BA architecture student studying at Plymouth University with a goal to become a fully qualified architect and advance my skills by working alongside professionals. I am a hard-working student, always working on time to meet deadlines. I enjoy stretching my creative abilities in each design project through drawing techniques or developing my skills on computer modelling programmes such as Revit. Within my course I enjoy researching the site and who I am designing for, as being able to speak to the client or the public is key in being able to develop a successful project. My positive attitude and confidence within the course was personally acknowledged by the Year 1 program leader after being invited to work as a student ambassador for my school. This continued into my second year where I was also selected to guide students in the digital fabrication suite. Communication and teamworking skills that I developed through previously working in retail, has aided me through my course by being able to communicate my design ideas well and working efficiently within groups. I hope to use these skills and develop them further working as a Part 1 Architectural Assistant.

#### **Education**

2015 - Present

# **BA(Hons) Degree | Plymouth University** Architecture - (Provisional) 2:1

## 2013 - 2015 **A-Level | South Downs College**

Maths - B Fine Art - C Philosophy - D

2008 - 2013

#### GCSE | Oaklands Catholic School

3 A\*, 6A's, B, C

Including 2 A\*'s in Maths and an A in English

#### Skills

- Strong interpersonal communication skills
- Ambitious and willing to learn
- Experience of leadership and efficient teamworking skills
- Good time management and organisational skills
- Full, clean UK driving license

### **Experience**

#### Student Ambassador | Plymouth University | January 2016 - Present

- Setting up and organising the studio for open days
- Providing information about the course to prospective students
- Guiding prospective students through creative workshops

#### Customer Assistant | Morrisons | September 2014 - September 2015

- Serve customers in a friendly and helpful manner
- Complete tasks on the shop floor to a high standard
- Deliver efficient and accurate service to all customers

#### Work Experience | Pick Everard | July 2014

- One week with building engineers learning AutoCAD and information about BREEAM
- Second week with architects designing a beach side home

#### Volunteer Retail Assistant | Marie Curie | July 2013 - September 2014

- Organise shop floor displays
- Serve customers in a friendly and helpful manner
- Sort donations to go out onto shopfloor

#### Work Experience | PWP Architects | July 2011

- Two weeks shadowing site visits and working on demo projects